Eugene Otto Weber Murman Watercolors of California Flora, 1941-1961
Louise M. Darling Biomedical Library History and Special Collections Division
Eugene Otto Weber Murman Watercolors of California Flora,
1941-1961
46
Murman, Eugene Otto Weber
26 boxes (52 linear ft.) and 78 35-mm. slides
University of California, Los Angeles. Library. Louise M. Darling Biomedical Library History and Special Collections Division Los Angeles, California 90095-1490
The Murman collection consists of 495 original watercolors and 26 photographs of California native plants, representing 85 different families and ca. 460 species. The paintings are scientifically accurate as well as artistic, each showing details of a branch and enlarged paintings of the flowers, fruit, and other diagnostic parts. Murman, originally a Russian banker, trained as a commercial artist after his emigration to the U.S. in 1905 and became a furniture designer in Los Angeles in 1906. After his retirement, he began traveling throughout California making preliminary sketches, color notes, and photographs of plants and collecting dried specimens; using these, Murman produced his body of watercolors in his home studio. Each series in the Container List represents a plant family. Each entry represents one plate, listing the scientific and common name, date & place of specimen collection, plus notes.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research. The copyright for the plates does not reside with UCLA. Some plates, mostly of conifers and other California trees, have been published by the University of California Press or Cachuma Press; rights to these plates will pass into the public domain in 2012. Contact the History & Special Collections Division of the Louise M. Darling Biomedical Library, UCLA, for further information.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 4430904
Acquisition Information
In the late 1940s or early 1950s, Murman began selling these watercolor plates to the UCLA Library's Department of Special Collections. At his death in 1962 the UCLA collection numbered 521 plates. In 1984, to mark the occasion of naming the UCLA Biomedical Library in honor of Louise M. Darling, its first librarian, the UCLA Library Special Collections Department transferred the Murman watercolors to the Louise M. Darling Biomedical Library.
Biography
Eugene O. Murman (Apr. 18, 1874 - Mar. 17, 1962) was born in St. Petersburg, Russia and developed an early interest in natural history and nature photography. After jobs as translator and clerk, he joined the foreign exchange department of the Russian Commercial and Industrial Bank and remained there until his immigration to the United States in 1905. Unable to find a banking position in New York, Murman decided on a change of career and spent a year in Germany being trained as a commercial artist. In 1906 he moved to Los Angeles where he soon became head designer for the California Furniture Company, which subsequently became W. & J. Sloane; he stayed with this firm for thirty-four years. During his free hours and on holidays he amassed a fine butterfly collection and became familiar with the plants and birds of his new home. His collection of hand-colored lantern slides was used to illustrate lectures on various natural history topics; these slides now reside in the Hancock Library of Biology & Oceanography at the University of Southern California. The butterfly collection was given to the Los Angeles County Museum of Natural History.
After his retirement, Murman and his second wife began a project to document the California flora in watercolors. Frequent collecting trips took them to many parts of the state and acquainted them with various botanists, forest rangers, and park naturalist, many of whom cooperated by sending living specimens of flowers and fruit, and assisted in identification of plants. Murman made color notes and preliminary sketches in the field and took black-and-white photographs for form and size, while Mrs. Murman took color photographs of the plants in their native habitat. With the aid of these field notes and photographs, as well as dried specimens, Murman then produced his outstanding series of watercolors in his home studio. His work received wide recognition, and just before his death he completed copies of four paintings for the collection of botanical art in the Hunt Botanical Library, Carnegie Institute of Technology.
Scope and Content
Eighty-five families of California plants are represented by Murman's watercolor plates, approximately 460 species. Specimens came from many California counties from north to south, with a fair number also collected in Oregon, Arizona, and other western locations. Each plate consists of an 8 x 10" watercolor (or photograph) on a 15 x 20" board.
Murman provided family, genus, and species (scientific and common names), location and date of specimen collection for each of the plates. The plates were numbered in the order of their accession at UCLA, so plate (and box) numbers serve only as location indicators; there is no taxonomic order to them. Murman's nomenclature is occasionally outdated, so some ingenuity and patience may be needed to locate a specific plant in the finding aid.
Each SERIES in the Container List represents a plant Family. Brackets indicate earlier or variant forms of the scientific family name; parentheses indicate the common name; the dates indicate inclusive collection dates. The "International Plant Name Index" (IPNI) (http://www.ipni.org) was used as the authority for placing a plate within a particular family (which sometimes differs from Murman's classification), and The National Plant Data Center's "Plants Database" (http://plants.usda.gov) served as the authority for the common family name used. Each ENTRY within a series represents a Murman plate. The genus, species, and common names of the specimens are in the form provided by Murman; no effort was made to standardize or update them. Again, the date is the date of specimen collecting; the notes include collecting location(s).
Related Collection: The Department of Special Collections, Young Research Library, UCLA in its Collection #1237 holds Murman archival material that extends one's knowledge of Mr. Murman's work and interests. Included are documents, lecture notes, photographs, sketches, slides, scrapbooks, and notebooks covering Russian cooking, ethnic costumes and artifacts, designs and interiors, gardens, flora, and travel.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Botany -- California
Container List
- Acanthaceae (Acanthus) Family. 1958, Series 1.; 1 entry
  - Beloperone californica (chuparosa).3/20/58 (Box 17, Folder 340)
    Twentynine Palms, San Bernardino County
- Aceraceae (Maple) Family. 1965, Series 2.; 4 entries
  - Acer circinatum (vine maple).5/15/54 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    McCloud, Siskiyou County
  - Acer glabrum (Sierra maple).7/20/54 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Acer macrophyllum (bigleaf maple).4/3/54 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Santa Barbara County
  - Acer negundo var. californicum (box elder)4/3/54 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Agavaceae (Century-plant) Family. 1941-1960, Series 3.; 7 entries
  - Yucca baccata (Spanish dagger).5/7/60, 9/60 (Box 23, Folder 453)
    Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden; Kaibab National Forest, AZ; plate indicates Family: Liliaceae
  - Yucca brevifolia (joshua tree).3/16/41 (Box 10, Folder 198)
    Mojave Desert; plate indicates Family: Liliaceae
  - Yucca mojavensis (Mojave yucca).3/30/41 (Box 10, Folder 199)
    Colorado Desert; plate indicates Family: Liliaceae
  - Yucca mojavensis (Mojave yucca).4/27/41, photograph (Box 10, Folder 200)
    Morongo Valley, San Bernardino County; plate indicates Family: Liliaceae
  - Yucca mojavensis (Mojave yucca; Spanish dagger).5/13/54 (Box 11, Folder 201)
    Joshua Tree National Monument, San Bernardino County; plate indicates Family: Liliaceae
  - Yucca mojavensis (Mojave yucca; Spanish dagger).5/14/54, photograph (Box 11, Folder 202)
  - Yucca whipplei (our Lord's candle; Spanish bayonet).5/1/57, 7/9/58 (Box 18, Folder 348)
    Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden; plate indicates Family: Liliaceae
- Aizoaceae (Fig-marigold [Carpet weed]) Family. 1961, Series 4.; 2 entries
  - Mesembryanthemum crystallinum (ice plant).4/27/61 (Box 19, Folder 379)
    Rincon Point, Ventura County
  - Mesembryanthemum edule (Hottentot fig).4/20/61 (Box 19, Folder 376)
    no collection place
- Amaryllidaceae (Amaryllis) Family. 1954-1955, Series 5.; 3 entries
  - Agave deserti (desert agave).5/14/54 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    In-ko-pah Gorge, Imperial County
  - Agave shawii (Shaw's agave).1/15/55, photograph (Box 20, Folder 382)
    Rancho Santa Ana, Orange County
  - Agave shawii (Shaw's agave).1/16/55 (Box 23, Folder 460)
    coast near Mexico border
- Anacardiaceae (Sumac) Family. 1953-1957, Series 6.; 5 entries
  - Rhus diversiloba (poison oak).3/30/53, 6/28/53 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    also slide #159; Glendale, Verdugo Hills, Los Angeles County
  - Rhus integrifolia (lemonade berry; mahogany sumac).1/25/53, 7/3/53 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    also slide #160; Glendale, Verdugo Hills, Los Angeles County; Santa Barbara County
  - Rhus laurina (laurel sumac).6/28/53, 7/26/53, 9/13/53 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    also slide #161; Verdugo Hills, Los Angeles County
  - Rhus ovata (sugar bush; sugar sumac).6/28/53, 6/1/53 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    also slide #162; Potrero Valley, Ventura County; Santa Barbara County
  - Rhus trilobata (squaw bush).3/7/57, 5/11/57 (Box 22, Folder 425)
    Santa Barbara Botanic Garden
- Apiaceae [Umbelliferae] (Parsley) Family. 1955, Series 7.; 3 entries
  - Angelica lineariloba (poison angelica).7/17/55 (Box 21, Folder 412)
    June Lake, Mono County; collected at 7,650' elevation
  - Heracleum lanatum (cow parsnip).7/17/55 (Box 21, Folder 411)
    Silver Lake, Mono County; collected at 7,250' elevation.
  - Sphenosciadium capitellatum (no common name).7/17/55 (Box 21, Folder 410)
    Silver Lake, Mono County; collected at 7,250' elevation
- Aristolochiaceae (Birthwort) Family. 1955, Series 8.; 1 entry
  - Aristolochia californica (Dutchman's pipe).2/18/55 (Box 24, Folder 463)
- Asclepiadaceae (Milkweed) Family. 1941-1960, Series 9.; 4 entries
  - Asclepias cordifolia (purple milkweed).6/1/42 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Madera County
  - Asclepias eriocarpa (milkweed).7/16/41 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Charlton Flats, Angeles National Forest
  - Asclepias erosa (desert milkweed).6/1/42 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Asclepias mexicana (Mexican milkweed).8/14/60 (Box 23, Folder 455)
    Canoga Park, Los Angeles County
- Asteraceae [Compositae] (Sunflower) Family. 1941-1961, Series 10.; 27 entries
  - Artemisia bolanderi (common sagebrush).8/20/54 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    Mammoth, Mono County; collected at 8,000' elevation
  - Artemisia pycnocephala (thickheaded sagebrush).6/13/57 (Box 25, Folder 495)
  - Baileye multiradiata (woolly marigold).2/3/59 (Box 17, Folder 331)
    Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden
  - Centaurea solstitialis (yellow star thistle; Barnaby's thistle).8/27/51 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    Marin County
  - Cichorium intybus (chicory).8/27/51 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Cirsium drummondii var. acaulescens (dwarf thistle).8/20/54, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 378)
    Arcularis Ranch, Mono County; collected at 8,000' elevation
  - Cirsium occidentale (western thistle).5/10/55 (Box 24, Folder 471)
    Verdugo Hills, Los Angeles County
  - Coreopsis calliopsidea (coreopsis).5/10/42 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    Mojave Desert, Los Angeles County
  - Coreopsis gigantea (giant coreopsis).1/5/58 (Box 18, Folder 359)
  - Coreopsis maritima (coast coreopsis).1/5/58 (Box 18, Folder 360)
  - Encelia farinosa (brittle bush; incienso).3/20/58 (Box 19, Folder 361)
  - Erigeron glaucus (seaside daisy).8/23/51 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    Pacific Grove, Monterey County
  - Eriophyllum nevinii (Catalina silver lace).5/11/57 (Box 25, Folder 494)
    Catalina & San Clemente Islands; Santa Barbara Botanic Garden
  - Franseria dumosa (burro bush).2/10/61 (Box 25, Folder 496)
    Borrego Springs, San Diego County
  - Geraea canescens (desert sunflower).4/22/61 (Box 25, Folder 497)
    Painted Canyon near Mecca, Riverside County
  - Grindelia robusta (gum plant).8/23/51 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Haplopappus linearifolius var. interior (narrowleaf goldenbush).4/18/58 (Box 19, Folder 362)
    Joshua Tree National Monument
  - Hymenoclea monogyra (cheese bush).2/10/61 (Box 25, Folder 498)
    Anza Borrego Desert State Park, San Diego County
  - Luina hypoleuca var. californica (no common name).6/3/41 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    Patrick Creek near Hwy. #199
  - Monoptilon bellioides (desert star).3/20/58 (Box 19, Folder 363)
  - Palafoxia linearis (Spanish needle).5/15/61 (Box 25, Folder 499)
  - Perezia microcephala (scapelote).8/31/51 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    Lompoc, Santa Barbara County
  - Peucephyllum schottii (pigmy cedar).2/20/54 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    Death Valley National Monument
  - Psathyrotes ramosissima (velvet rosettes).4/22/61 (Box 25, Folder 500)
  - Silybum marianum (milk thistle).6/28/53 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Tetradymia spinosa longispina (cotton thorn).5/15/54 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    Joshua Tree National Monument, San Bernardino County
  - Wyethia helenioides (no common name).6/3/41 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    Lake County
- Berberidaceae (Barberry) Family. 1955-1958, Series 11.; 4 entries
  - Berberis aquifolium (Oregon grape).2/18/55, 6/11/55 (Box 24, Folder 464)
  - Berberis nevinii (Nevin barberry).3/26/55, 6/11/55 (Box 24, Folder 465)
  - Berberis pinnata (California mahonia).3/7/57, 6/13/57 (Box 22, Folder 423)
  - Berberis piperiana (piper mahonia).2/3/58, 6/28/57 (Box 18, Folder 341)
- Betulaceae (Birch) Family. 1955, Series 12.; 6 entries
  - Alnus rhombifolia (white alder).1/20/55, 7/4/55 (Box 20, Folder 384)
    North Hollywood, Los Angeles County
  - Alnus rubra (red alder; Oregon alder).2/23/55, 3/23/55, 8/5/55 (Box 24, Folder 466)
    Inverness, Marin County; Klamath, Del Norte County
  - Alnus sinuata (Sitka alder).5/23/55, 9/14/55 (Box 24, Folder 467)
    Regional Botanic Garden, Berkeley, CA; Mount Hood, OR
  - Alnus tenuifolia (thinleaf alder).5/23/55 (Box 24, Folder 468)
    Regional Botanic Garden, Berkeley, CA
  - Betula fontinalis (water birch).5/11/55, 7/16/55 (Box 24, Folder 469)
    Rock Creek Canyon, Mono County
  - Corylus rostrata var. californica (California hazel).4/5/55, 11/2/55 (Box 24, Folder 470)
    Mills College, Oakland, Alameda County and also Josephine County, OR
- Bignoniaceae (Bignonia) Family. 1954, Series 13.; 1 entry
  - Chilopsis linearis (desert willow; desert catalpa).5/10/54, 10/24/54 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Morongo Valley and Dagget, San Bernardino County
- Brassicaceae [Cruiciferae] (Mustard) Family. 1958-1961, Series 14.; 3 entries
  - Dithyrea californica (spectacle pod).2/10/61 (Box 26, Folder 508)
  - Stanleya pinnata (desert plume).5/25/58 (Box 18, Folder 343)
  - Streptanthus inflatus (squaw cabbage; desert candle).4/22/60 (Box 23, Folder 459)
    Shoshone, Inyo County
- Burseraceae [Burceraceae] (Torchwood) Family. 1957-1960, Series 15.; 2 entries
  - Bursera microphylla (elephant tree; torote)., photograph by Dalton E. Merkel (Box 20, Folder 381)
  - Bursera microphylla (elephant tree; torote).7/28/57, 8/30/60 (Box 23, Folder 451)
- Buxaceae (Box) Family. 1957-1958, Series 16.; 1 entry
  - Simmondsia chinensis [Simmondsia californica] (goat nut; jojoba).6/28/57, 1/6/58 (Box 18, Folder 342)
    Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden; plate indicates species: californica
- Cactaceae (Cactus) Family. 1940-1960, Series 17.; 41 entries
  - Carnegia gigantea (saguaro).5/22/51 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    5 miles north of Laguna Dam, Imperial County; Utah; Arizona; Sonora, Baja Calif.; Colorado River west of mouth of Bill Williams Crater
  - Carnegia gigantea (saguaro).3/17/40, photograph (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Saguaro Nationa Monument, Arizona; photo includes Rosaleen Meek Murman
  - Carnegia gigantea (saguaro).2/23/50, photograph (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Saguaro National Monument, Arizona; photo includes Eugene Murman
  - Carnegia gigantea (saguaro).2/23/50, photograph (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Saguaro National Monument, Arizona
  - Cereus emoryi (golden-spined cereus; cunado).4/24/59 (Box 16, Folder 313)
  - Cereus engelmannii (calico cactus).3/30/41 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Borrego Valley, San Diego County
  - Echinocactus acanthodes (barrel cactus).3/30/41 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Echinocatus acanthodes (barrel cactus; bisnaga).4/26/41, photograph (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Colorado desert
  - Echinocactus johnsonii (eight-spined hedgehog).4/22/60 (Box 23, Folder 447)
    14.3 miles northwest of Shoshone, Inyo County; diameter: 4.5"; height: 6"
  - Echinocerus engelmannii (hedgehog cactus).3/30/41, photograph (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Echinocereus engelmannii (saint's cactus).5/25/58, photograph by Rosaleen M. Murman (Box 18, Folder 357)
  - Echinocereus mojavensis (Mojave hedgehog cactus).4/27/41 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Joshua Tree National Monument, Keys Ranch
  - Echinocereus mojavensis (Mojave hedgehog cactus).4/27/41, photograph (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Mamillaria dioica (fishhook cactus).4/19/41 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Mamillaria microcarpa (Graham's nipple cactus).7/25754 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Colorado Desert
  - Opuntia acanthocarpa (deer-horn cactus).5/20/54 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Mojave Desert, San Bernardino County
  - Opuntia basilaris (beavertail cactus).3/30/41 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Opuntia basilaris (beavertail cactus).3/30/41, photograph (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Opuntia bigelovii (jumping cholla).4/27/41 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Opuntia chlorotica (golden prickly pear).5/27/59 (Box 16, Folder 314)
  - Opuntia covillei var. piercei (Coville's tuna).5/10/60 (Box 19, Folder 380)
  - Opuntia echinocarpa (cholla).3/30/41 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Opuntia echinocarpa (golden cholla).3/30/41, photograph (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Opuntia echinocarpa var. parkeri (staghorn cholla).5/10/60 (Box 23, Folder 449)
  - Opuntia erinacea (hedgehog cactus).4/21/54 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Opuntia megacantha (prickly pear; la tuna rancheria).9/12/59, color photograph by Rosaleen M. Murman (Box 16, Folder 315)
    Mission la Purisima Concepcion, Lompoc, Santa Barbara County
  - Opuntia megacantha (prickly pear; la tuna rancheria).9/12/59 (Box 16, Folder 316)
  - Opuntia megacarpa (large-fruited tuna).4/24/59 (Box 16, Folder 317)
  - Opuntia mojavensis (Mojave prickly pear).5/20/54 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Opuntia occidentalis (no common name).5/11/41 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Newport
  - Opuntia parishii (dead cactus).6/12/60 (Box 23, Folder 448)
  - Opuntia parryi (no common name).5/17/41 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Tujunga Wash
  - Opuntia prolifera (coast cholla).4/19/41 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Opuntia ramosissima (lead-pencil cholla).6/24/59 (Box 16, Folder 318)
  - Opuntia serpentina (San Diego cholla).4/16/59 (Box 16, Folder 319)
  - Opuntia treleasei (no common name). (Box 2, Folder 37)
    no collection date or place
  - Opuntia ursina (grizzly bear cactus). (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Opuntia ursina (grizzly bear cactus).5/25/58, photograph (Box 18, Folder 358)
    photo by Rosaleen M. Murman; Joshua Tree National Monument
  - Opuntia vaseyi (no common name). (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Opuntia vaseyi (no common name).5/17/41 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Opuntia x. munzii (no common name).6/15/60 (Box 23, Folder 450)
- Calycanthaceae (Sweet-shrub) Family. 1957, Series 18.; 1 entry
  - Calycanthus occidentalis (spice bush).6/6/57, 8/15/57 (Box 21, Folder 419)
- Capparaceae [Capparidaceae] (Caper) Family. 1953, Series 19.; 1 entry
  - Isomeris arborea (burro fat; bladder pod).6/28/53 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    also slide #163; Santa Barbara County
- Caprifoliaceae (Honeysuckle) Family., Series 20.; 6 entries
  - Lonicera interrupta (chaparral honeysuckle).5/4/59, 7/17/59, 10/18/59 (Box 16, Folder 320)
    Mulholland Drive, Los Angeles County
  - Lonicera involucrata (twinberry).2/18/59 (Box 17, Folder 321)
  - Sambucus glauca (blueberry elder).4/28/55, 7/26/55 (Box 20, Folder 389)
  - Sambucus racemosa var. callicarpa (coast red elderberry)6/13/57 (Box 20, Folder 386)
    Inverness, Marin County
  - Symphoricarpos mollis (creeping snowberry).6/13/57 (Box 23, Folder 441)
  - Symphoricarpos rotundifolius (mountain snowberry).7/16/55, 9/55 (Box 22, Folder 440)
    Mammoth, Mono County; collected at 8,200' elevation
- Caryophyllaceae (Pink) Family. 1941, Series 21.; 1 entry
  - Silene californica (indian pink).6/3/41 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Chenopodiaceae (Saltbush) Family. 1954-1961, Series 22.; 6 entries
  - Atriplex hymenelytra (desert holly).2/20/54 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Atriplex hymenelytra (desert holly).2/20/54, photograph (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Eurotia lanata (winter fat; romeria).4/29/59 (Box 17, Folder 328)
  - Grayia spinosa (hop-sage).3/30/60, 5/17/58 (Box 23, Folder 457)
  - Sarcobatus vermiculatus (greasewood).7/10/57, 8/15/57 (Box 22, Folder 430)
    male & female specimen collected on separate dates; Alkaline Flats, Owens Lake, Inyo County
  - Suaeda torreyana (ink weed).2/10/61 (Box 26, Folder 507)
- Convolvulaceae (Morning-glory) Family., Series 23.; 1 entry
  - Cuscuta californica (dodder). (Box 3, Folder 57)
    no collection date; widely distributed in California; parasite, most frequent in So. Calif. on erigonum and adenostoma (fr.Jepson)
- Cornaceae (Dogwood) Family. 1942-1951, Series 24.; 1 entry
  - Cornus nuttallii (mountain dogwood).6/30/42, fall 1951 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    also slide #164; Madera County
- Crassulaceae (Stonecrop) Family. 1941-1959, Series 25.; 5 entries
  - Cotyledon laxa (rock lettuce).6/3/41 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Dudleya pulverulenta (chalk dudleya).7/7/59 (Box 17, Folder 322)
  - Echeveria saxosa (rock echeveria).5/12/54 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Sedum species (no common name).6/13/41 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    Hwy. #199, Patricks Creek, Del Norte County
  - Stylophyllum hassei (Catalina stylophyllum).11/10/57 (Box 22, Folder 429)
    Catalina Island
- Cucurbitaceae (Gourd) Family. 1959, Series 26.; 1 entry
  - Echinocystis macrocarpa (chili-cojote).3/22/59 (Box 17, Folder 323)
- Cupressaceae (Cypress) Family. 1942-1961, Series 27.; 17 entries
  - Chamaecyparis lawsoniana (Port Oxford cedar; Lawson cypress).4/15/43 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    also slide #165; Oregon
  - Chamaecyparis nootkatensis (Alaska yellow cedar).9/6/61 (Box 26, Folder 515)
    Northern Forest Experiment Station, Juneau, Alaska; known in Siskiyou County, north-east slope of Mt. Emily, and Little Grayback, CA, near 5,000' elevation
  - Cupressus bakeri (Bakers cypress).5/19/61 (Box 26, Folder 514)
    Burney Springs, Lassen National Park, Hat Creek
  - Cupressus forbesii (tecate cypress; Forbes cypress)2/11/57 (Box 25, Folder 483)
    Guatay, San Diego County
  - Cupressus goveniana (Gowen cypress).10/2/42 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    also slide #166; Descanso, San Diego County
  - Cupressus macnabiana (McNab cypress).2/1/43 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    also slide #167; headwaters of Elder Creek, south-west Tehama County, 3,000' elevation
  - Cupressus macnabiana var. (McNab cypress var.).12/1/42 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    Siskiyou County, section 14, T.45 north, R.4 west, M.D.M.
  - Cupressus macrocarpa (Monterey cypress).1/20/57, 4/10/57 (Box 25, Folder 481)
    Santa Cruz, Santa Cruz County; male & female also collected Point Lobos, Monterey County
  - Cupressus pygmaea (pigmy cypress; Mendocino cypress).1/10/57 (Box 25, Folder 484)
    Fort Bragg, Mendocino County
  - Cupressus sargentii (Sargent cypress).1/23/57, 3/16/57 (Box 25, Folder 482)
    Mt. Tamalpais, Marin County
  - Cupressus stephensonii (Cuyamaca cypress).1/27/61 (Box 26, Folder 513)
    Mt. Cuyamaca, San Diego County, 5,000' elevation
  - Juniperus californica (California juniper).1/20/59 (Box 17, Folder 329)